As your code base grows, you may find yourself needing to re-evaluate what
عند زيادة أساس الكود، قد تجد نفسك تحتاج لإعادة تقييم
information is essential for your documentation.
ما المعلومات الأساسية لتوثيقك.
Deciding what goes into your readme is entirely up to you.
تحديد ما يتم وضعه في "readme" يرجع لك.
But let's go over a few common sections and then use cases in a readme.
لكن دعنا ننتقل بين مجموعة الأقسام الشائعة ثم حالات استخدام في "readme".
Including copyright or licensing information, or at least a link to it,
بما في ذلك معلومات الترخيص أو حقوق النشر أو على الأقل رابط لذلك،
is always a good idea, no matter how large or small a project.
فكرة صائبة دائمًا، لا يهم حجم المشروع الصغير أو الكبير.
By default, you retain full rights to your code even if you don't
افتراضيًا، تحتفظ بحقوق كاملة لكودك حتى عندما
include a license, but it's a safer bet to be explicit about this.
لا يكن لديك ترخيص، لكن لدواعي الأمن من الأفضل الوضوح بشأن ذلك.
Often, what you really want to do though,
وفي الغالب سترغب في القيام بذلك،
is allow others to contribute to your project.
حيث يسمح للآخرين بالمساهمة في مشروعك.
In this case, it's super important to include a license.
في هذه الحالة، من الأهمية بمكان إدخال ترخيص.
You can choose to include the full license in your readme itself,
يمكنك اختيار إدخال ترخيص كامل في ملف "readme"،
or you can link out to it from your readme.
ويمكنك الربط من الخارج عبر ملف readme.
Choosing which license is a bit beyond the scope of this course, but
اختيار الترخيص يتجاوز نطاق الدورة،
I've included a link to a handy resource in the instructor notes,
لكن قمت بإدخال رابط لمصدر في ملاحظات الموجه،
appropriately titled choosealicense.com to help you out with this.
تحت عنوان choosealicense.com لمساعدتك في ذلك.
In the spirit of contribution, if you have a preferred way for others to
عبر الإسهام، إذا كان لديك طريقة مفضلة للآخرين للإسهام في مشروعك،
contribute to your project, the readme is the right place for that, too.
فإن ملف readme هو المكان المناسب لذلك.
Briefly outlining simple steps, a style guide or
باختصار وضع خطوات بسيطة أو دليل إرشادي
whatever information you'd like others to know about contributing,
أو المعلومات التي ترغب أن يعرفها الآخرون عن الإسهام،
is a great way to make your project more accessible for those wanting to help.
إنها طريقة رائعة لتمكين الآخرين من الدخول لمشروعك للمساعدة في ذلك.
Some services, like ones that check to see if all your tests are passing,
بعض الخدمات، مثل تلك المتعلقة بمعرفة نتائج الاختبارات، ستسمح،
will provide special graphics, known as shields, for your readme's.
برسومات خاصة معروفة باسم الدروع لملفات readme.
These shields are useful because they're provided by a third party, and
هذه الدروع مفيدة لأن من يقدمها هو طرف خارجي،
let your users know helpful information about your code.
وتدع المستخدمين لديك يعرفون المعلومات المفيدة عن كودك.
If this seems a bit confusing for now, don't worry too much about it.
إذا كان مربكًا الآن، لا تقلق كثيرًا عن ذلك.
I know when I started writing documentation these really confused me
أعلم ذلك حيث عندما قمت ببداية التوثيق، كان ذلك مربكًا لي
because I thought I needed to have them.
لأنني كنت أواجه ذلك.
Once you've written lots of tests in your code,
بمجرد كتابتك لكثير من الاختبارات في كودك،
these shields will become useful.
هذه الدروع مفيدة.
But when you're just getting started, don't worry too much about it.
لكن عندما تبدأ، لا تقلق كثيرًا بشأن ذلك.
A word of caution, don't make your life more complicated than it needs to be.
كتحذير، لا تجعل حياتك أكثر تعقيدًا مما ينبغي.
Allow your documentation to grow with the code base and
دع التوثيق يزيد من مساحة أساس الكود
only add new information as needed.
وأضف المعلومات الجديدة بحسب الضرورة.
We've looked at just a few potential sections you might want to include in
نناقش أقسام صغير محتملة قد ترغب في تضمينها
your readme as you document your code but don't limit yourself to just these.
في ملفات readme حيث توثق كودك لكن لا تقيد نفسك بذلك.
As your code base grows,
بما أنك تسعى لزيادة أساس الكود،
which sections might also make sense to add to your readme?
ما الأقسام التي يكون من المفيد إضافتها لملفات readme؟
Known bugs, frequently asked questions, press that your project has received,
لمعرفة المشكلات والأسئلة الشائعة، اضغط للتأكيد على استلامك المشروع،
a table of contents or pictures of your cat.
جدول المحتويات أو الصور.
Select as many as you think apply.
حدد كل ما تعتقد أنه ينطبق.